是避难基地
Oh, it's a sanctuary base!
外太空探险
Deep space exploration.
欢迎来到地狱
"Welcome to hell."
你们在这儿干什么
What are you lot doing here?
那是黑洞
That's a black hole.
但那不可能啊
But that's impossible.
这颗行星在黑洞同步轨道上缓慢运行
This lump of rock is suspended in perpetual geostationary orbit around that black hole,
而不被吸入
without falling in.
似乎是某种能量源支撑着我们
There's some sort of power source holding us here.
我们正进行地下钻探 希望能发现它
We're drilling down to try and find it.
塔迪斯不见了
The Tardis is gone.
不管下面是什么 绝不是自然现象
Well, whatever it is down there, it's not a natural phenomenon.
曾经存在某种文明
And there was some form of civilization.
他们埋藏了什么
They buried something.
它们叫什么
What are they called?
它们是怪奇 低等奴隶种族
They're the Ood. Basic slave race.
怪奇出了点问题
There's something happening with the Ood.
你们将侍奉它
And you will worship him.
告诉托比 我们发现了他所说的文明
You can tell Toby we've found his civilization.
那是恶魔的语言 它已经苏醒了
These are the words of the Beast. And he has woken.
我曾被永久禁锢
I have been imprisoned for eternity.
到此为止
But no more.
深渊开启了
The Pit is open
我自由了
and I am free!
开火
Open fire!
我们正在稳定
We're stabilizing.
回到轨道了
We've got orbit.
博士
Doctor?
博士 能听见吗
Doctor, can you hear me?
博士 艾达 你们在吗
Doctor, Ida, are you there?
是我
It's me!
它们来了
But they're coming.
是怪奇
It's the Ood.
它们疯了
They've gone mad.
有多少
How many of them?
全部 五十个
All of them, all 50.
丹尼 让开
Danny, out of the way.
但他们有武器 交流装置
But they're armed. It's the interface device.
我不知道怎么弄的 可它们把它用作武器
I don't know how, but they're using it as a weapon.
关闭一号门
Close door 1.
开启一号门 关闭一号门
Open door 1. Close door 1.
封锁 封闭一号门
Lockdown! Seal door 1!
杰佛逊 情况怎么样
Jefferson, what's happening there?
弹药所剩无几 你呢
I've got very little ammunition, sir. How about you?
我有一把栓枪
All I've got is a bolt-gun
只有一发炮弹
with, uh, all of one bolt.
只能打倒足足一整只怪奇 这下可好了
I could take out a grand total of one Ood. Fat lot of good that is.
鉴于情况紧急 我建议启用…九号方案
Given the emergency, I recommend strategy nine.
九号方案 批准
Strategy nine agreed.
好的 我们需要聚齐所有人
Right, we need to get everyone together.
洛斯 艾达和博士呢 有回音吗
Rose, what about Ida and the Doctor? Any word?
收不到回复 什么也没有
I can't get a reply. just nothing.
我试了很久 但是…
I keep trying, but it's...
不 抱歉 我很好 还活着
No, sorry. I'm fine. Still here!
你不早说 你这个蠢…
You could have said, you stupid...
小心
Careful!
总之 我和艾达都还好 你们好
Anyway, it's both of us, me and Ida. Hello!
但是封印开启了
But the seal opened up.
它不见了
It's gone.
只留给我们一个深坑
All we've got left is this chasm.
有多深
How deep is it?
很难说 似乎是个无底洞
Can't tell. Looks like it goes down forever.
"深渊开启了"
The Pit is open.
那个声音就是这么说的
That's what the voice said.
但是什么也没有 没东西从里面出来吧
But there's nothing. I mean, there's nothing coming out?
是的 没有恶魔的迹象
No, no, no. No sign of the Beast.
它说是撒旦
It said Satan.
行了 洛斯 别胡思乱想
Come on, Rose. Keep it together.
真有这种东西吗
Is there no such thing?
博士
Doctor?
博士 告诉我"根本没有这种东西"
Doctor, tell me there's no such thing.
艾达 我建议你们撤退 马上
Ida, I recommend that you withdraw immediately.
可是我们大老远…
But we've come all this way.
这是命令 撤退
Okay, that was an order. Withdraw!
那东西开启时 整个行星都移位了
When that thing opened, the whole planet shifted.
再多一英寸 我们就要掉进黑洞了
One more inch and we fall into the black hole
行动立即结束
so this thing stops right now.
但是上面情况也不乐观 怪奇造反了
But it's not much better up there with the Ood.
我启动了九号方案
I'm initiating strategy nine
所以 我要你们两个立即上来 没…
so I need the two of you back up top immediately. No...
艾达 艾达
Ida? Ida?
你怎么看
What do you think?
他都下命令了
He gave an order.
是的 但你怎么看
Yeah, but what do you think?
它说 "我是诱惑"
It said, "I am the temptation."
如果下面有什么东西
If there's something in there,
为什么它还躲在下面
why is it still hiding?
也许
Maybe
我们只打开了监狱大门 没打开牢房
we opened the prison but not the cell.
我们应该下去
We should go down.
我去
I'd go.
你呢
What about you?
哦 当然 不过仔细想想
Oh, in a second. But then again...
这太符合人类精神了
That is so human.
前往天使也不敢涉足之处
Where angels fear to tread.
即使是现在 站在深坑的边缘
Even now, standing on the edge,
就是这种感觉 对吧
it's that feeling you get, yeah?
就在你头脑深处
Right at the back of your head.
那种冲动
That impulse,
那种奇特微妙的冲动
that strange little impulse.
那种疯狂的声音在呼喊
That mad little voice saying,
"继续 继续 往前走"
"Go on, go on, go on.
"跨过去 去吧…"
"Go over, go on."
也许它正依赖着这一点
Maybe it's relying on that.
斯科特中尉 生命中唯一一次
For once in my life, Officer Scott,
我想说…
I'm going to say...
撤退
retreat.
现在我知道我真是老了
Now I know I'm getting old.
洛斯 我们回来了
Rose, we're coming back.
这一天最好的消息
Best news I've heard all day.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
他感染了 你也看到的 他把那东西带上了船
He's infected. He brought that thing on board. You saw it.
你现在要开始伤害自己人了 你是这么想的吗
Are you gonna start shooting your own people now? Is that what you're gonna do?
是吗
Is it?
如果有必要的话
If necessary.
如果有必要 你必须先杀了我 你会怎么做
Well, then you'll have to shoot me, if necessary. So what's it gonna be?
看看他的脸
Look at his face.
无论那是什么 它已经走了
Whatever it was, it's gone.
它跑到了怪奇身上 你看见的
It passed into the Ood. You saw it happen.
他是清白的
He's clean.
一有复发的迹象 我马上射杀他
Any sign of trouble, I shoot him.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
我也不知道
I don't know.
你能记起什么吗
Can you remember anything?
只记得 它很生气
Just... It was so angry.
它是愤怒 狂暴 还有…死亡
It was fury and rage and death.
是它
It was him.
是恶魔
It was the Devil.
来吧
Come here.
什么是九号方案
What's strategy nine?
开启空气阻隔舱
Open the airlocks.
我们待在密封舱里很安全
We'll be safe inside the lockdown.
而怪奇将被吸入真空宇宙
The Ood will get thrown out into the vacuum.
那我们回去就是一场屠杀
So we're going back to a slaughter?
魔鬼的行为
The Devil's work.
好了 已就位 带我们上去
Okay, we're in. Bring us up.
上升 三 二 一
Ascension in three, two, one.
这里是黑暗
This is the darkness.
是我的领地
This is my domain.
你们这些渺小的 活在光里的生物
You little things that live in the light,
赖以生存的微弱太阳
clinging to your feeble suns
最终也消亡殆尽
which die, in the end...
那不是怪奇 什么东西在通过它们说话
That's not the Ood. Something is talking through them.
只有黑暗会留存
Only the darkness remains.
这里是六号避难基地 扎克里·克洛斯·弗雷恩船长
This is Captain Zachary Cross Flane of Sanctuary Base 6,
代表火炬木档案馆 请你报上你的身份
representing the Torchwood Archive. You will identify yourself.
你知道我的名字
You know my name.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
你们将葬身于此 所有人
You will die here, all of you.
这颗行星是你们的坟墓
This planet is your grave.
是它
It's him.
如果你是恶魔 那回答我 是哪一个
If you are the Beast, then answer me this. Which one, hmm?
因为自从你离开后 宇宙忙得很
'Cause the universe has been busy since you've been gone.
出现的宗教比天上的星星还多
There's more religions than there are planets in the sky.
方舟教 圣史教 基督教 狂热教
The Arkiphets, Quoldonity, Christianity, Pash Pash,
新犹太教 圣克拉教 流浪汉教
Neo-Judaism, San Claar, the Church of the Tin Vagabond.
你是哪个教的恶魔
Which devil are you?
所有
All of them.
什么 那你是"神话背后的真相"
What, then you're the truth behind the myth?
这家伙认识我
This one knows me
我也认识他
as I know him.
他是自己本族的杀手
The killer of his own kind.
你怎么会沦落到这块石头上
How did you end up on this rock?
光之信徒起来反抗我
The Disciples of the Light rose up against me
将我永远锁在无底深渊
and chained me in the Pit for all eternity.
这是什么时候的事
When was this?
时间之前
Before time.
什么意思
What does that mean?
时间之前
Before time.
"时间之前"是什么意思
What did "before time" mean?
在时间 光明 空间 物质诞生之前
Before time and light and space and matter.
在大劫难之前
Before the cataclysm.
在这个宇宙诞生之前
Before this universe was created.
不可能 没有生命能存在于那里
That's impossible. No life could have existed back then.
那就是你信仰的宗教
Is that your religion?
这是一种信仰
It's a belief.
你一无所知
You know nothing.
你们所有人 如此渺小
All of you, so small.
船长 对指挥恐惧不已
The captain, so scared of command.
士兵 仍被妻子的眼神所纠缠
The soldier, haunted by the eyes of his wife.
科学家 仍在挣脱父亲的阴影
The scientist, still running from daddy.
撒谎的男孩
The little boy who lied,
处子
the virgin
还有迷途的女孩
and the lost girl.
远离家乡
So far away from home.
这个勇敢的孩子 很快就要死在战场上
The valiant child who will die in battle so very soon.
博士 那是什么意思
Doctor, what does that mean?
洛斯 别听它的
Rose, don't listen.
它是什么意思
What does it mean?
你们都得死
You will die
而我将永生
and I will live.
那究竟是什么东西
What the hell was that?
那东西曾出现在我脑海里
I had that thing inside my head.
博士 这是什么意思
Doctor, what did it mean?
我们怎么办 杰佛逊
What do we do? Jefferson.
扎克 九号方案情况怎么样
Captain, what's the situation with strategy nine?
轨道 行星 黑洞…这一切都是真的
...the black hole, everything's true!
失去视频信号
We've lost pictures.
博士 它怎么会知道这些
How did it know...
谁有分析表吗…
Did anyone get an analysis?
杰佛逊
Jefferson.
停下
Stop.
所有人都停下
Everyone just stop!
怎么办 回话
What do we do? Report...
告诉过你
Told you
你们想听黑暗中的声音 那就听我的
If you want voices in the dark, then listen to mine.
那东西在利用你们的原始恐惧
That thing is playing on very basic fears.
黑暗 童年 噩梦 诸如此类
Darkness, childhood, nightmares, all that stuff.
恶魔就是这样工作的
But that's how the Devil works.
一个好的心理学家也这样
Or a good psychologist.
它怎么会认识我父亲
How did it know about my father?
它的版本哪里比我的高明了
Okay, but what makes his version of the truth any better than mine, hmm?
因为我看见的是
'Cause I'll tell you what I can see. Humans.
人类 伟大的人类
Humans. Brilliant humans.
穿越广袤太空的人类
Humans who travel all the way across space.
乘坐着狭小的飞船 来到黑洞的轨道
Flying in a tiny little rocket right into the orbit of a black hole,
为了探索发现  这太伟大了
just for the sake of discovery. That's amazing!
听见了吗 伟大 你们所有人
Do you hear me? Amazing. All of you.
船长 队员 年长的 年轻的 朋友们
The captain, his officer, his elder, his juniors, his friends.
我们最大的优势是 恶魔只有他自己
All with one advantage, the Beast is alone,
而我们不是
we are not.
如果我们能利用这点来对抗它…
If we can use that to fight against him...
缆绳断了
The cable's snapped!
出去
Get out!
博士 缆绳断了
Doctor, we lost the cable.
博士 你没事吧
Doctor, are you all right?
博士
Doctor?
通讯中断
Comms are down.
博士 听见了吗
Doctor, can you hear me?
仍有生命迹象 但太空舱丢失了
I've still got life-signs, but we've lost the capsule.
说话啊 有人吗
Say something! Are you there?
没有出路了
There's no way out.
他们被困在下面了
They're stuck down there.
我们的空气还能支持多久
How much air have we got?
六十分钟
Sixty minutes.
55分钟
Fifty-five.
我们必须把他们救上来
But we've got to bring them back.
他们在十英里深处 我们没有这么长的缆绳了
They're ten miles down. We haven't got another ten miles of cable.
船长
Captain,
情况汇报
situation report?
是怪奇
It's the Ood.
它们正在毁坏门闩 试图闯入
They're cutting through the door bolts. They're breaking in.
25号门这里也是
Yes. Same on door 25.
还能支撑多久
How long is it gonna take?
门框结构很简单 只能支撑十分钟
Well, it's only a basic frame. Should take ten minutes.
八分钟
Eight.
我这里有安全门 也许可以支持久一点
I've got a security frame, might last a bit longer
但帮不了你们
but that doesn't help you.
好的 那我们得阻止它们 或逃出去 或双管齐下
Right. So we need to stop them or get out or both.
我同意双管齐下 可是怎么做
I'll take both, yeah? But how?
你听见博士的话了 为什么那怪物打断他
You heard the Doctor. Why do you think that thing cut him off?
因为他的话有道理 他教导你们寻找出路
'Cause he was making sense. He was telling you to think your way out of this.
来吧 首先 我们需要亮光
Come on! For starters, we need some lights.
扎克 这里一定还有后备能源
Zack, there's got to be some sort of power somewhere.
我无能为力
There's nothing I can do.
什么船长 困在这儿 按按钮
Some captain! Stuck in here, pressing buttons.
博士就是这个意思 按正确的按钮
That's what the Doctor meant. Press the right buttons.
它们摧毁了发电机
They've gutted the generators.
但是发射器有独立供给
But the rocket's got an independent supply.
如果能变更线路…
If I could reroute that...
杰佛逊先生 打开支路管道
Mr Jefferson, open the bypass conduits.
覆盖安全设置
Override the safety.
支路管道开启 长官
Opening bypass conduits, sir.
引导发射器燃料
Channelling rocket feed.
倒计时 三二一
In three, two, one.
通电
Power.
成功了
There we go!
让这里有光吧
Let there be light!
九号方案怎么样了
What about that strategy nine thing?
能量不够 需要100%
Not enough power, needs 100 percent.
我们得找到出路
Right, we need a way out.
扎克 杰佛逊先生 你们开始想办法
Zack, Mr Jefferson, you start working on that.
托比 你呢
Toby, what about you?
我不是军人 什么也做不了
I'm not a soldier. I can't do anything.
不 你是考古学家
No, you're the archaeologist.
关于深渊你知道些什么吗
What do you know about the Pit?
什么也不知道 甚至无法翻译文字
Nothing, we can't even translate the language.
等一下 也许…
Hold on. Maybe...
什么
What is it?
自从那东西进入我头脑以后
Since that thing was inside my head,
那些文字变得有意义
it's like the letters make more sense.
那就开始工作 任何能翻译的东西
Well, get to work. Anything you can translate, just, anything.
至于你 丹尼小子
As for you, Danny boy,
你负责怪奇 有办法阻止他们吗
you're in charge of the Ood. Any way of stopping them?
我不知道
I don't know.
那就想想办法
Then find out.
越早控制基地 就能越早救出博士
The sooner we get control of the base, the sooner we can get the Doctor out.
现在去吧 好好干
Now get going. Shift.
我们还有这些缆绳 最好利用起来
We've got all this cable. We might as well use it.
滑轮分离了
The drum is disconnected.
可以改装一下 把它连通
We could adapt it. Feed it through.
然后呢
And then what?
延绳下滑
Abseil
进入深渊
into the Pit.
滑下去 好吧
Abseil. Right.
氧气就要耗尽了
We're running out of air
没有回头路 这是我们唯一的选择
with no way back. It's the only thing we can do,
即使这是我们最后的成就
even if it's the last thing we ever achieve.
我会回去的
I'll get back.
洛斯还在上面
Rose is up there.
也许回去的关键 就是找出深渊下的秘密
Well, maybe the key to that is finding out what's in the Pit.
这是半个好主意
Well, it's half of a good plan.
那另一半呢
What's the other half?
我下去 不是你
I go down, not you.
打开五 六 七号接口
Open junctions five, six, seven.
过滤器16变更至24号 开始
Reroute filters 16 to 24. Go.
有很多病毒能阻止怪奇
There's all sorts of viruses that could stop the Ood.
问题是 基地没有样本
Trouble is, we haven't got them on board.
没什么大不了 我们没有的东西可多了
Well, that's handy, listing things we haven't got.
我们没有泳池 也没有超市
We haven't got a swimming pool either, or a Tesco's.
哦 天哪
Oh, my God.
行了
It says yes!
我能试试
I can do it!
设想一下
Hypothetically,
如果改变监控器 播送某种信号
if you flip the monitor, broadcast a flare,
就可以改变感应场 太妙了
it can disrupt the telepathy. Brainstorm!
怪奇会怎么样
What happens to the Ood?
溃不成军
It'll tank them, spark-out!
那好啊 就这么做
There we are, then. Do it!
但是
I know, but...
必须从中央监控器发出信号
I'd have to transmit from the central monitor.
我们得去怪奇居住区
We need to go to Ood Habitation.
那我们就这么做
That's what we'll do, then.
杰佛逊先生 长官 有办法出去吗
Mr Jefferson, sir, any way out?
差不多吧
just about.
基地下面有一组维护隧道网络
There's a network of maintenance tunnels running underneath the base.
从这儿应该能通过
We should be able to gain access from here.
通风管道
Ventilation shafts.
多谢参考 但是那里面不通风
I appreciate the reference, but there's no ventilation.
实际上 一点空气都没有
No air, in fact, at all.
是为机器设计的 生命体不能通过
They were designed for machines, not life forms.
但是 我可以从这里操纵氧气区域
But I can manipulate the oxygen field from here,
形成不同的空气隔间
create discrete pockets of atmosphere.
如果手动控制 我能帮助你们通过隧道
If I control it manually, I can follow you through the network.
好的 我们在下面走 你让空气紧跟我们
Right. So we go down and you make the air follow us by hand?
怎么做
How
是你让我按按钮的
You wanted me pressing buttons.
是的 我要求的
Yep, I asked for it.
我们要去怪奇居住区 制定一条路线
Okay, we need to get to Ood Habitation. Work out a route.
这样应该能撑住
That should hold it.
怎么样
How's it going?
不错 应该能行
Fine. Should work.
现在又觉得这主意没那么好了
Doesn't feel like such a good idea now.
又出现了 那种渴望
There it is again. That itch.
下去 下去 下去 下去
Go down, go down, go down, go down!
跳跃的冲动
The urge to jump.
你知道这种感觉是从哪来的吗
Do you know where it comes from, that sensation?
是基因遗传
Genetic heritage.
自从我们还是树上的灵长类时就有了
Ever since we were primates in the trees.
是身体在测试我们
It's our body's way of testing us,
计算我们能否跳到下一根树枝上
calculating whether or not we can reach the next branch.
不 不是这样
No, that's not it.
没那么美好
That's too kind.
不是跳跃的冲动 比这更深沉
It's not the urge to jump. It's deeper than that.
是坠落的冲动
It's the urge to fall.
博士
Doctor!
你还好吧
You okay?
不错 谢谢
Not bad, thanks.
深渊的墙 似乎和洞穴内的一样
The wall of the Pit seems to be the same as the cavern,
只不过 没那么多而已
just not much of it.
二十英尺深处有个硬壳
There's a crust about 20 feet down.
然后…
And then...
没什么 只是深渊
nothing, just the Pit.
好了 继续往下
Okay, then. Lower me down.
来吧
Well, here we go, then.
丹尼
Danny!
等一下 核对中
Hold on, just conforming.
丹尼 必须马上走了
Danny, we've got to go now.
快点
Come on.
好了
There!
把它插入监控器 怪奇的日子就难过了
Put that in the monitor and it's a bad time to be an Ood!
我们会回来的 明白吗
We're coming back. You got that?
我们会回到这里 并且把博士救出来
We're coming back to this room and we're getting the Doctor out.
好了 丹尼 你先走 然后泰勒小姐
Danny, you go first, then Miss Tyler,
然后托比 我断后
then Toby. I'll go last in defensive position.
来吧 越快越好
Now come on, quick as you can!
天哪 好臭啊
God, it stinks.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事 好得很
Yeah, laughing.
走哪条路
Which way do we go?
笔直前进 直到我喊停
Just go straight ahead. Keep going till I say so.
这个角度不够美 丹尼
Not your best angle, Danny.
喂 别闹了
Oi, stop it.
我这儿还更糟呢  - 喂
Don't know, could be worse. - Oi!
直走 找到7.1号接口
Straight on till you find junction 7.1.
保持呼吸
Keep breathing.
我正在填充氧气
I'm feeding you air.
有我在
I've got you.
到达7.1节点了 长官
We're at 7.1, sir.
好的 我看到了
Okay, I've got you.
我正给下一区域灌氧
I'm just aerating the next section.
有点紧急 长官 你能快点吗
Getting kind of cramped, sir. Can't you hurry up?
我只有一半能量
I'm working on half power here.
别抱怨了
Stop complaining.
杰佛逊说"别抱怨了"
Mr. Jefferson said stop complaining.
我听见了
I heard.
他听见了
He heard.
空气变稀薄了
The air's getting a bit thin.
这回他抱怨了
He's complaining now.
我听见了
I heard.
丹尼 是你吗
Danny, is that you?
我心情不太好
I'm not exactly happy.
我还在输送空气 必须给下一区域灌氧
I'm just moving the air. I've got to oxygenate the next section.
现在 保持冷静 否则感觉会更糟
Now, keep calm or it's gonna feel worse.
那是什么
What was that?
杰佛逊先生 那是什么
Mr Jefferson, what was that?
什么声音
What was that noise?
船长 出什么事了
Captain, what was that?
五号生活区的接口被打开了 肯定是怪奇干的
The junction in Habitation 5 has been opened. It must be the Ood.
它们进隧道了
They're in the tunnels.
打开接口
Open the gate.
氧气还没输送完毕
I've got to get the air in!
别管了 打开
just open it; sir!
它们在哪 接近吗
Where are they? Are they close?
不知道 我看不见它们
Don't know. I can't tell. I can't see them.
计算机不把怪奇识别为生命体
The computer doesn't register Ood as proper life forms.
谁这么设计的
Whose idea was that?
打开接口
Open the gate!
丹尼 立刻左转
Danny, turn left, immediate left!
怪奇追来了
The Ood, sir,
你能困住它们吗 切断空气
can't you trap them? Cut off the air?
不行 这样会切断你们的氧气
Not without cutting off yours.
丹尼 右转 往右
Danny, turn right, go right.
加快速度 它们要赶上了
Go faster. They're gonna catch up.
我留在这儿断后
I'll maintain defensive position.
你不能停下
You can't stop!
泰勒小姐 这是我的职责
Miss Tyler, that's my job.
你有你的任务 别管我
You've got your task, now see to it.
你们听见他的话了 快走
You heard what he said, now shift!
8.2 打开8.2号
8.2, open 8.2!
扎克 打开8.2号接口
Zack, open 8.2!
必须先充氧
I've got to aerate it.
打开 马上
Open it now!
我正全力以赴
I'm trying!
丹尼 停下 这样没用的
Danny, stop it. That's not helping!
扎克 打开它
Zack, get it open!
杰佛逊 我得关闭8.1号 才能打开8.2号
Jefferson, I've got to open 8.2 by closing 8.1.
你必须马上通过接口 快
You've got to get past the junction, now move!
这是命令 快走
That's an order, now move!
我快控制不住氧气了 杰佛逊
I'm gonna lose oxygen, Jefferson.
自动设置无法更改
I can't stop the automatics!
好了 快走
That's it, come on, come on!
丹尼 左转 朝9.2号走 这是最后一关
Danny, turn left and head for 9.2. That's the last one.
杰佛逊 你必须加快速度
Jefferson, you've got to move faster!
约翰 快  - 杰佛逊先生 快
John! Move! Move! Mr. Jefferson!
快 不要停
Come on! Keep going!
很遗憾地告诉您 长官
I regret to inform you, sir,
我慢了一步
I was a bit slow.
速度大不如前了
Not so fast these days.
我不能打开8.1号 约翰
I can't open 8.1, John.
其他人会失去空气
Not without losing air for the others.
没关系 长官
And quite right, too, sir.
希望给他们争取了一些时间
I think I bought them a little time.
我无能为力 约翰
There's nothing I can do, John.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你做得很好 长官
You've done enough, sir.
这种情况下 您是一个出色的船长
Made a very good captain under the circumstances.
我想问 既然你不能给这区加氧
Might I ask, if you can't add oxygen to this section,
那你能加快抽除氧气吗
can you speed up the process of its removal?
我不明白 你说什么
I don't understand. What do you mean?
如果我要选择自己的死法
Well, if I might choose the manner of my departure, sir,
死于缺氧似乎比死在怪奇手中
lack of air seems more natural than, well...
更自然一点
let's say, death by Ood.
谢谢你了 长官
I'd appreciate it, sir.
保佑你 杰佛逊先生
Godspeed, Mr Jefferson.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
报告
Report.
约翰·梅纳德·杰佛逊队员
Officer John Maynard Jefferson, PKD...
光荣牺牲
deceased, with honours,
公元43000年 1月2日
43K 2.1.
扎克
Zack,
我们到达最后一个接口了
we're at the final junction.
9.2号
9.2.
还有…
And, uh.
请记录下我的敬意 他救了我们的命
If my respects could be on record, he saved our lives.
记录在案 开启9.2号接口
Noted. Opening 9.2.
放下9.2号 扎克 放下
Lower 9.2! Zack, lower it!
回去回去
Back, back, back!
回不去了 8.2号封闭了 我们被困住了
We can't go back. Look, 8.2's sealed off. We're stuck!
来 往上
Come on! Up!
快点 托比 往上爬
Come on. Toby, come on!
托比 出来
Toby, get out of there!
救我 天啊 帮帮我
Help me. Oh, my God! Help me!
走这边
It's this way!
快点
Hurry UP!
放进去
Get it in.
丹尼 搞定它
Danny, get it done.
发射信号
Transmit!
我在弄 我正在放进去
I'm trying. I'm trying. I'm getting it in...
阻止它们
Stop them!
丹尼 快发射信号
Danny, get that thing transmitting.
你成功了 我们成功了
You did it! We did it!
扎克 我们成功了 怪奇停止了
Yes! Oh, yes! Zack, we did it. The Ood are down!
现在回去救博士
Now we've got to get the Doctor.
我马上来
I'm on my way
你代表全宇宙的恶魔
You get representations of the horned beast right across the universe,
千万个世界的神话传说
in the myths and legends of a million worlds.
地球
Earth,
达科尼亚
Draconia,
瓦康萨丁
Vel Consadine.
半人神
Daemos,
卡拉德战神
the Kaled God of War.
同样的形象反复出现
It's the same image over and over again.
也许 这种概念来自某个源头
Maybe that idea came from somewhere,
源源不断地涌出
bleeding through.
存在于每个人内心深处
A thought at the back of every sentient mind.
从这里散发
Emanating from here?
有可能
Could be.
如果这里是源头
But if this is the original,
那意味着那是真的吗
does that make it real?
意味着它就是真的魔鬼
Does that make it the actual Devil, though?
如果你愿意相信的话
Well, if that's what you want to believe.
也许归根到底 魔鬼只是一种概念
Maybe that's what the Devil is in the end, an idea.
没了
That's it.
缆绳只有这么长
That's all we've got.
有什么反馈讯号吗
You getting any sort of read out?
什么也没有
Nothing.
可能还有几英里深
Could be miles to go yet.
或者 也可能只有三十英尺 谁知道呢
Or it could be 30 feet. There's no way of telling.
三十英尺摔不死我
I could survive 30 feet.
不 你别想 我这就拉你上来
Oh, no, you don't. I'm pulling you back up.
你干什么
What are you doing?
就算你拉我上去 也只能在上面等死
You bring me back, we're just gonna sit there and run out of air.
我必须下去
I've got to go down.
不行
But you can't.
博士 不要
Doctor, you can't!
就当这是信仰之举好了
Call it an act of faith.
我不想一个人死在这里
I don't want to die on my own.
我明白
I know.
博士 你在吗
Doctor, are you there?
博士 艾达 听得见吗
Doctor, Ida, can you hear me?
通讯仍然中断
The comms are still down.
我可以通过中央控制台修复
I can patch them through the central desk
并加强讯号 给我一点时间
and boost the signal. Just give me a minute.
我没问过 你有没有什么信仰或…
I didn't ask. Have you got any sort of faith?
不算有
Not really.
我成长在新古典主义公理教会
I was brought up Neo-Classic Congregational.
因为我妈妈是…
Because of my mum, she was...
我的老母亲
My old mum.
不 我没有信仰
But, no, I never believed.
新古典主义有魔鬼吗
Neo-Classics. Have they got a devil?
不 没有这样的 只是…
No, not as such. just, um...
只有人的罪恶
the things that men do.
说到底都是一回事
Same thing in the end.
那你呢
What about you?
我相信…还有很多我没见过的事物
I believe... I believe I haven't seen everything, I don't know.
很奇怪 对吧
It's funny, isn't it?
人类编造的那些法则
The things you make up, the rules.
如果那东西说它来自宇宙之外 我可能会相信
If that thing had said it came from beyond the universe, I'd believe it.
可是早于宇宙
But before the universe?
不可能
Impossible.
不符合我的法则
Doesn't fit my rule.
也许这就是我浪迹天涯的原因
Still, that's why I keep travelling.
证明自己是错的
To be proved wrong.
谢谢 艾达
Thank you, Ida.
别走
Don't go!
如果通讯恢复了
If they get back in touch...
如果能联络到洛斯
If you talk to Rose,
请告诉她…
just tell her...
告诉她…
Tell her...
哦 她会明白的
Oh, she knows.
博士 你在吗
Doctor, are you there?
博士 艾达 听得见吗
Doctor, Ida, can you hear me?
你在吗 博士
Are you there, Doctor?
他走了
He's gone.
什么意思 他走了
What do you mean, he's gone?
他掉进了深渊
He fell... into the Pit.
我不知道有多深 一米又一米
And I don't know how deep it is, miles and miles and miles.
你说什么 他掉下去了
What do you mean, he fell?
我阻止不了他
I couldn't stop him.
他提到了你的名字
He said your name.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
艾达
Ida?
我们没办法救你上来
There's no way of reaching you.
没有缆绳 没有备用
No cable, no backup.
你又在十英里深处
You're ten miles down.
我们下不去
We can't get there.
你应该看看这里 扎克
You should see this place, Zack.
太美了
It's beautiful.
我一直想探索世界
I wanted to discover things,
现在我来了
and here I am.
我们必须放弃基地
We've got to abandon the base.
我回去就宣布这项任务不安全
I'm declaring this mission unsafe.
我们能做到就是 确保没人再来这里
All we can do is make sure no one ever comes here again.
这样我们也永远不能发现真相
But we'll never find out what it was.
也许这是最好的结果
Well, maybe that's best.
是啊
Yeah.
斯科特队员  - 没关系
Officer Scott... It's all right.
走吧
Just go.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
你也是
And you.
丹尼 托比
Danny, Toby,
切断输送链接 准备好制动火箭
close down the feed-links. Get the retrotopes online.
登上火箭 系好安全带 准备离开
Then get to the rocket and strap yourselves in. We're leaving.
我不走
I'm not going.
洛斯 我们有足够的位置
Rose, there's space for you.
不 我要等博士
No, I'm gonna wait for the Doctor,
他也会等我的
just like he'd wait for me.
抱歉 但他已经死了
I'm sorry, but he's dead.
你们不了解他
You don't know him.
他不会死的
'Cause he's not.
我告诉你 他不会…
I'm telling you, he's not.
即使他死了 我怎么能这样离开他
And even if he was, how could I leave him
让他一个人 孤零零地在下面
all on his own, all the way down there?
不行 我要留下
No, I'm... I'm gonna stay.
我很抱歉这样对你
Then I apologise for this.
丹尼 托比 固定住她
Danny, Toby, make her secure.
不 不 不 放手
No! No! No! Stop! No! Let me go!
放开我
Get off me!
放手 我不走
I'm not leaving! No!
我已经失去太多人了
I have lost too many people.
我不能扔下你不管
I am not leaving you behind.
带她上去
Let's get her on board.
它是不是动了
Did that one just move?
是感应场的作用 它在自我回应
It's the telepathic field. It's reasserting itself!
快点 登上火箭 走
Move it. Get to the rocket! Move!
我还有气
I'm breathing.
气垫层缓解了冲击力
Air cushion to support the fall.
下面能呼吸 艾达
You can breathe down here, Ida.
能听见吗 艾达
Can you hear me, Ida?
打开安全扣B C
Dislocating B clamp, C clamp.
能量提升至最大 托比 反馈线路怎么样
Raising Blu-Nitro to maximum. Toby, how's the Negapact feed-line?
完毕 准备出发 长官
Clear, ready to go, sir.
看在上帝份上 带我们离开这儿
For God's sake, get us out of here!
船长 我们好像有一个问题旅客
Captain, I think we're gonna have a problem passenger.
盯好她
Keep an eye on her.
没事了 洛斯 我们很安全
It's all right, Rose. We're safe.
我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere!
让我出去 快放我出去
Get me out of this thing. Get me out!
准备
And
发射
liftoff!
火箭走了
The rocket.
带我回那个星球
Take me back to the planet.
带我回去
Take me back!
否则怎样
Or what?
否则我会开枪
Or I'll shoot.
你会吗
Would you, though?
你真的会开枪吗
Would you really?
这是博士希望看到的吗
Is that what your Doctor would want?
抱歉 太晚了 看看外面
I'm sorry, but it's too late anyway. Take a look outside.
我们不能回去了
We can't turn back.
这也是博士所希望的 不是吗
This is what the Doctor would have wanted. Isn't that right?
某次大战的历史 人对抗恶魔
History of some big battle. Man against Beast.
不知道你能不能听到 艾达 但愿能
I don't know if you're getting this, Ida. Hope so.
总之 人类打败了恶魔 并囚禁了它
Anyway, they defeated the Beast and imprisoned it.
也许这就是钥匙
And maybe that's the key.
或是大门 或者栅栏
Or the gate or the bars.
有什么好笑的
What's the joke?
没什么 我们撑过来了
Just... We made it.
我们逃脱了 我们做到了
We escaped. We actually did it.
不是所有人
Not all of us.
我们还没出去呢
We're not out of it yet.
我们是史上首批飞离黑洞的人
We're still the first people in history to fly away from a black hole.
托比 告诉我放射强度
Toby, read me the stats.
引力漏斗还在 长官
Gravity funnel holding, sir.
它还在
Oh, it's holding.
我接受你的存在
I accept that you exist.
我不必承认你是什么 但我认同你的物质存在
I don't have to accept what you are. But your physical existence, I give you that.
我不明白 有人似乎在期待我的到来
I don't understand. I was expected down here.
给我提供了安全降落 和足够的空气
I was given a safe landing and air.
你有求于我 是什么
You need me for something. What for?
是不是要我…
Have I got to...
是要请求接见 还是…
I don't know, beg an audience or...
要举行仪式吗
Is there a ritual?
某种咒语 召唤还是魔法
Some sort of incantation or summons or spell?
这些我都不信 它们是真的吗
All these things I don't believe in, are they real?
说话啊 告诉我
Speak to me! Tell me!
你不想说
You won't talk
还是…不能说
or you can't talk.
等等 稍等
Hold on, hold on.
等一下 让我…
Wait a minute. just let me...
哦 不对
Oh! No.
是的 不对
Yes! No.
仔细想想 你之前说过话
Think it through. You spoke before,
我听过你的声音 智能的声音
I heard your voice. An intelligent voice.
不 不仅如此 聪明极了
No, more than that. Brilliant!
但是 看看现在的你
But looking at you now,
我所能看见的
all I can see...
只有…一头野兽 一个动物
is beast. The animal,
只是躯体
just the body.
你只是躯体 肉身 你的精神怎么了
You're just the body, the physical form. What's happened to your mind, hmm?
它走了吗 你的智慧在哪里
Where's it gone? Where's that intelligence?
哦 不
Oh, no.
放射强度53 重力66.5
Stats at 53. Funnel stable at 66.5.
外部压力稳定
Hull pressure constant.
保持平稳 一路回家
Smooth as we can, sir. All the way back home.
目标设置为地球
Coordinates set for planet Earth.
很久很久以前 你就被囚禁了
You were imprisoned a long time ago.
宇宙诞生之前还是之后 里面还是外面 无所谓
Before the universe, after, sideways, in between, it doesn't matter.
监狱牢不可破
The prison is perfect.
是绝对的 永恒的
It's absolute. It's eternal.
哦 对了
Oh, yes!
一旦打开监狱 引力场就会消失
Open the prison, the gravity field collapses.
整颗星球就会坠入黑洞
This planet falls into the black hole.
你一逃跑 你就死定了 太妙了
You escape, you die. Brilliant!
但那只是躯体
But that's just the body.
只有躯体被困在这儿
The body is trapped, that's all.
魔鬼只是一个概念 在所有的文明中 都只是概念
The Devil is an idea. In all those civilizations, just an idea.
但是概念无法抹杀
But an idea is hard to kill.
概念可以逃跑
An idea can escape.
精神 恶魔的思想 可以逃跑
The mind, the mind of the great Beast, the mind can escape.
啊 没错
Oh, but that's it!
不是你 是你的狱卒给我提供了空气
You didn't give me air, your jailers did!
设计之初 他们就预见到了现在
They set this up all those years ago.
他们需要我活着
They need me alive.
因为如果你想逃跑 我就能阻止你
Because if you're escaping, then I've got to stop you!
如果我毁了监狱 你的肉身也毁于一旦
If I destroy your prison, your body is destroyed,
你不介意吧
your mind with it.
但你够聪明 懂得用这一套来设计我
But then you're clever enough to use this whole system against me.
如果我毁了这颗星球 引力场就会消失
If I destroy this planet, I destroy the gravity field.
火箭将失去保护
The rocket. The rocket loses protection,
坠入黑洞
falls into the black hole.
我必须牺牲洛斯
I have to sacrifice Rose.
没有道理
It doesn't make sense.
我们逃脱了 但它有无数种方法可以杀了我们
We escaped, but there's a thousand ways it could have killed us.
可以让我们缺氧窒息 可以让我们活活烧死
It could have ripped out the air or, I don't know, burnt us or anything.
但它却让我们走了 为什么
But it let us go. Why?
除非它想让我们走
Unless it wanted us to escape.
喂 洛斯 帮我个忙
Hey, Rose, do us a favour.
闭嘴
Shut up.
快了 我们马上就要飞出黑洞范围
Almost there. We're beyond the reach of the black hole
倒计时 40 39…
in 40, 39...
这是个圈套
So that's the trap
或是测试 还是最后的审判 我也不知道
or the test or the final judgement, I don't know.
如果我杀了你 就会害死她
But if I kill you, I kill her.
不过
Except that implies
在这个神与魔的惊天大阴谋中
in this big, grand scheme of gods and devils,
她只是个小小的受害者
that she is just a victim.
但我经历过宇宙间风风雨雨
But I've seen a lot of this universe.
我见过假神 恶神
I've seen fake gods and bad gods
半人半神 痴迷乱神
and demigods and would-be gods,
在这所谓的万神殿中
and out of all that, out of that whole pantheon,
如果说我相信什么的话
if I believe in one thing,
就一件事
just one thing,
我相信她
I believe in her.
怎么了 发生什么事了
What happened? What was that?
他在做什么
What's he doing?
引力漏斗消失了 发生了重力崩塌
We've lost the funnel! Gravity collapse!
什么意思
What does that mean?
我们逃不出去了
We can't escape.
我们正笔直冲向黑洞
We're heading straight for the black hole.
这就是你的自由
This is your freedom!
死的自由
Free to die!
你将坠入黑洞 而我与你同行
You're going into that black hole and I'm riding with you!
那颗行星在移动
It's the planet. The planet's moving.
它在坠落
It's falling.
我是狂暴 是愤怒 是凶残  - 是它 是托比
I'm the rage and the bile and the ferocity! It's Toby!
我是王子 是愚者 是痛苦
I am the prince and the fool and the agony!
我是罪孽 是恐惧 是黑暗
I'm the sin and the fear and the darkness!
待在原地 飞船很不稳定
Stay where you are. The ship's not stable.
怎么回事 他到底是什么
What is he? What the hell is he?
我将永生
I shall never die!
我的思想将永存
The thought of me is forever.
存在于在人类淌血的心中
In the bleeding hearts of men,
存在于他们的空虚 迷茫和欲望中
in their vanity and obsession and lust!
没人能毁灭我 没人
Nothing shall ever destroy me. Nothing.
下地狱吧
Go to hell.
启动紧急防护罩
Emergency shield!
我们仍然没有引力漏斗
We've still lost the gravity funnel.
无法摆脱黑洞
We can't escape the black hole.
但我们阻止它了
But we stopped him.
博士也会这么做的
That's what the Doctor would have done.
某种胜利
Some victory.
我们要进黑洞了
We're going in.
行星脱离了轨道 正在坠落
The planet's lost orbit. It's falling!
星球没了
The planet's gone.
对不起
I'm sorry.
加速
Accelerate.
我已经尽力了
I did my best.
不过 我们也是首批进入黑洞的人类
But, hey, the first human beings to fall inside a black hole.
这听上去怎么样
How about that?
见证历史
History.
怎么了
What happened?
我们转向了
We're turning.
我们在调头
We're turning around.
我们在远离黑洞
We're turning away!
抱歉劫持了飞船 船长
Sorry about the hijack, Captain.
这里是塔迪斯
This is the good ship Tardis.
先说要紧事 有没有一个洛斯·泰勒在你们船上
First things first, have you got a Rose Tyler on board?
我在这里 是我
I'm here! It's me!
天哪 你在哪里
Oh, my God! Where are you?
正在带你们回家
I'm just towing you home.
重力无重力 我的族人基本上发明了黑洞
Gravity-shmavity. My people practically invented black holes.
实际上 就他们干的
Well, in fact, they did.
再过几分钟 我们就平安无事了
Couple of minutes, we'll be nice and safe.
对了 船长
Oh, and Captain,
做笔交易好吗
can we do a swap?
如果你给我洛斯·泰勒 我就给你艾达·斯科特
Say, if you give me Rose Tyler, I'll give you Ida Scott.
怎么样
How about that?
她还活着 感谢上帝
She's alive! Yes. Thank you, God.
是的 有点缺氧 应该没事
Bit of oxygen starvation, but she should be all right.
我没能救下怪奇
I couldn't save the Ood.
时间只允许我回去一趟
I only had time for one trip.
它们和行星一起去了
They went down with the planet.
进入安全空间
Entering clear space.
航行结束 任务完成
End of the line. Mission closed.
不知道 我记不清了
I don't know. I can't remember.
看上去像个警亭
Well, it looked like a box.
一个警亭 什么意思
What do you mean, a box?
下面货舱里 有个蓝色大警亭
Well, down in the hold, a big blue box.
突然冒出来 我也不清楚
It just appeared. I don't know.
扎克 我们走了 一路顺风
Zack, we 'll be off now. Have a good trip home.
下次你们对什么感到好奇的话
And the next time you get curious about something...
有什么用 冒失莽撞的人类
Oh, what's the point? You'll just go blundering in.
人类啊
The human race!
博士 你在下面发现了什么
But, Doctor, what did you find down there?
那个怪物是什么
That creature, what was it?
我不知道 始终没有破译那些文字
I don't know. Never did decipher that writing.
这样也不错
But that's good.
我无所不知的那天 我将停止旅行
The day I know everything, I might as well stop.
你觉得它是什么
What do you think it was, really?
我觉得…
I think
我们战胜它了 这就够了
we beat it. That's good enough for me.
它说我会死在战场上
It said I was going to die in battle.
它撒谎了
Then it lied.
好了 向上向前 艾达
Right! Onwards, upwards. Ida,
下次再见
see you again maybe.
希望如此
I hope so.
谢谢 先生们
And thanks, boys!
再等一下 博士
Hang on though, Doctor,
你还没告诉我们 你们俩究竟是谁
you never really said. You two, who are you?
就是一段传说罢了
Oh, the stuff of legend.
这是来自六号避难基地的最后汇报
This is the final report of Sanctuary Base 6.
托比·泽德队员 光荣牺牲
Officer Tobias Zed, deceased, with honours.
43000年1月2日
43K 2.1.
怪奇 1 α 1 光荣牺牲
Also, Ood 1 Alpha 1, deceased, with honours.
怪奇 1 α 2 光荣牺牲
Ood 1 Alpha 2, deceased, with honours...
亮灯
Lights!
我是你们的救世主
I am your salvation.
这是宇宙的声音
The sound of the universe.
什么意思
What does it mean?
他的名字是博士
His name is the Doctor.
什么博士
Doctor what?
把这女孩给我找来
Find me that girl!
看我们俩 完全是陌生人 现在我却在向你亮内裤
Here we are, complete strangers, and I'm flashing you my knickers.
离抓到博士了又近一步了
One step closer to catching the Doctor.
我认识你吗
Don't I know you?